<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Activity on 忘言阁 Zenith John's Nonsense</title><link>https://zenith-john.github.io/tags/activity/</link><description>Recent content in Activity on 忘言阁 Zenith John's Nonsense</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zenith-john.github.io/tags/activity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mathematical Physics Seminar, Topic: Quantum Cohomology 2024.9-2025.1</title><link>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/mathematical_physics_seminar_2024_autumn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/mathematical_physics_seminar_2024_autumn/</guid><description>Aim Learning recent progress on quantum cohomology. For details, see syllabus. Time and Place Time: TBD Place: TBD (most likely in Shuangqing complex building A) Prerequisite Algebraic geometry and symplectic geometry. Syllabus We may choose from following topics in quantum cohomology or discuss anything of participants interest. Quantum D-module after Iritani. [1,2] Quantum cohomology of birational Calabi-Yau manifolds. [3] Dubrovin conjecture. [4,5] Representation theory from quantum cohomology. [6,7] First talk</description></item><item><title>Enumerative Geometry Seminar, Topic: Aspects of Gromov-Witten theory, 2023.2-2023.6</title><link>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/enumerative_geometry_seminar_2023_spring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/enumerative_geometry_seminar_2023_spring/</guid><description>Aim Learning Gromov-Witten theory from several different aspects. For details, see syllabus. Time and Place Time: Every Tuesday 09:50-11:25 (From Feb 28th) Place: Ning Zhai(宁斋) S11 Prerequisite Algebraic geometry and symplectic geometry. Syllabus We will cover following topics in Gromov-Witten theory Gromov-Witten/Pandharipande-Thomas correspondence (Nantao Zhang) Gromov-Witten theory and topological recursion (Jinghao Yu) The equivariant Gromov-Witten theory of \(\mathbb{P}^{1}\) (Weilin Su) Graph sum formula</description></item><item><title>Algebraic Geometry Reading Seminar, Topics: Intersection Theory, 2022.9-2023.1</title><link>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/algebraic_geometry_seminar_2022_fall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/algebraic_geometry_seminar_2022_fall/</guid><description>Aim Learning algebraic cycles and intersection theory in algebraic geometry. Time and Place Time: Every Tuesday, 09:50-11:25. Place: Ning Zhai(宁斋) W11 Tentative schedule Time Speaker Content 2022-09-13 Nantao Zhang Chapter 1 of Fulton 2022-09-20 Liyuan Ye Chapter 2 of Fulton 2022-09-27 Yuting Liu Chapter 3 of Fulton 2022-10-04 Yuting Liu, Yunling Chen continue, Chapter 4,5 of Fulton 2022-10-11 Yunling Chen continue 2022-10-18 Nantao</description></item><item><title>Enumerative Geometry Seminar, Topic: Homological Mirror Symmetry, 2022.2-2022.6</title><link>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/enumerative_geometry_seminar_2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zenith-john.github.io/post/enumerative_geometry_seminar_2022/</guid><description>Aim Provide attendees enough information of Fukaya category and derived category of coherent sheaves to understand the main statement of homological mirror symmetry. \[D^{\pi}{\rm Fuk}(X) \cong D^{b}{\rm Coh}(X^{\vee})\] Also, I hope this learning seminar will give us a good chance to communicate with others in Tsinghua University, so feel free to invite others! Time and Place Start from 2022.02.27. Every Sunday, 09:30-11:00 Jinchunyuan West Building, Conference Room 1. (近</description></item></channel></rss>